<TEI xml:space="preserve" xml:lang="en"
 xml:base="ex-epidoctemplate.xml" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Miniature Perirrhanterion or Thymaterion Base Fragment With Dipinto</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority/>
                <idno type="filename"/>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>ASCSA Corinth</repository>
                        <idno>C-1968-343</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support>
                                    <p>
                                        <material>  </material> 
               
                                        <objectType>Single corner-base fragment, broken left and right and top. Hard, pale, yellowish-buff fabric, shading towards pink at core; well-levigated but with a few large inclusions. Slipped and polished outside, with elaborate painted decoration; inside slipped and smoothed. 
                                        Viewer's-left front corner of base of miniature perirrhanterior or thymeterion (taking inscribed face as front); rectangular portion of base handmade and attached to wheelmade circular portion. 
                                        Decoration and dipinto: rectangular base, vertical face (front side): outlined cruedly in much-faded and flaked black with very crude single dotted-fret pattern within; a single red verticle stroke at extreme corner; upper platform: red, with much flaked black corner palmette outlined
                                        in red; circular rising portion: torus in 2 degrees and rising panel to antoher offset in at least 2 degrees; outer edge of upper torus black (worn and faled) and upper edge red (somewhat flaked)</objectType>
                                    </p>
                                </support>
                            </supportDesc>
                            <layoutDesc>
                                <layout>one line of text in a curved arc around the torus edge </layout>
                            </layoutDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc>
                            <handNote> outer edge of upper torus black (worn and flaked) and upper edge red (somewhat flaked); located on panel above
                            </handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history>
                        <origin>
                            <origPlace>Corinth, Greece, Drain, red pebbly top strosis</origPlace>
                            <origDate></origDate>
                        </origin>
                        <provenance type="found"> Lot 5197 (4th C.BL)
                        </provenance>
                        <provenance type="observed"> ACSCA Museum Basement, Drawer 221
                        </provenance>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <facsimile>
        <graphic url="https://ascsa.net/image?type=preview&amp;id=Corinth%3AImage%3Adigital%202017%201573"/> 
    </facsimile>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="edition" xml:space="preserve">
                <ab>
                    <lb n="1"/>DAMATR[---]
                </ab>
            </div>
            <div type="apparatus">
                <p>RS Stroud: not Demeter</p>
            </div>
            <div type="translation">
                <p>"to Demeter"</p>
            </div>
            <div type="commentary">
                <p></p>
            </div>
            <div type="bibliography">
                <p></p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>