<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:space="preserve" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Double Cruet</title>
            <editor xml:id="ktomczyszyn" role="editor">Karolina Tomczyszyn</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Dartmouth College</authority>
                <idno type="filename">C-2015-39</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>ASCSA Corinth</repository>
                        <idno>C-2015-39</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support> <objectType>Double cruet</objectType>with flaring ring foot with flat resting surface and convex undersurface, hemispherical body to horizontal shoulder and domed upper body rising to tall round knob with slightly pointed apex. Two round cylindrical spouts attached at 180 degrees to each other at top of shoulder. One spout has circular horizontal rim with squared lip pinched to form spout pointed to outside of vessel. Other spout has circular horizontal rim that flattens to upturned tapered lip. One flattened strap handle attached at mid-point of both spouts to form arch across body. Double internal chambers. Upper chamber has convex bottom taking up half vessel and connected to spout-less spout, lower chamber of vessel and connected to spouted spout. <material>Fine pale brown clay with rare small-medium spherical round white inclusions</material>
                                    <dimensions unit="metre"><dim type="height" subtype="handle">0.139</dim><dim type="height" subtype="knob">0.103</dim><dim type="diameter" subtype="foot">0.05</dim><dim type="diameter" subtype="foot" max="0.102"></dim><dim type="diameter" subtype="spouts">0.045</dim><dim type="weight" unit="gram">0.186</dim></dimensions>
                                <p> Current condition: Complete profile. Twelve joining fragments, preserving all of base, most of body, both spouts and handle. Some chips  </p>
                                </support>
                            </supportDesc>
                            <layoutDesc>
                                <layout>Fully black glazed except for undersurface of foot. Single reserved (or scraped) bands at edge of shoulder and upper body bordering continuous single row of white painted dots. Upper body to just below graffito has series of long incised vertical lines creating sixteen panels (eight on either side of spouts) containing two semicircular incised lines with dot in center at bottom and triangle of three white painted dots in middle up to single incised band below transition to knob. Top of handle has running garland motif of dilute glaze leaves and white dot berries flanked by single incised bands</layout>
                            </layoutDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc>
                            <handNote>Graffito below knob
                            </handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history>
                        <origin>
                            <origPlace>Corinth</origPlace>
                            <origDate>first century BCE</origDate>
                        </origin>
                        <provenance type="found" when="2015-05-26">South Stoa, well fill, 35th deposit from top
                        </provenance>
                        <provenance type="observed">ASCSA Corinth Basement; Bay 72, Shelf 5 <!-- Simone, did you actually autopsy this? When? -->
                        </provenance>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change who="#ktomczyszyn" when="2022-03-25">Transcribed and encoded text (at EpiDoc workshop)</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <facsimile>
        <graphic url="C-2015-39.jpeg"/>
    </facsimile>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="edition" xml:space="preserve" xml:lang="grc">
                <ab>
                    <lb n="1"/>ΙΛΚ
                </ab>
            </div>
            <div type="apparatus">
                <p>external apparatus criticus (if applicable)</p>
            </div>
            <div type="translation">
                <p>ILK</p>
            </div>
            <div type="commentary">  
            </div>
            <div type="bibliography">
                <bibl xml:id="mus-C-2015-39">Corinth Museum Index card C-2015-39</bibl>        <p>Similar to C-1965-320 (Pemberton 1989, Corinth 18.1, cat. 199) and C-1947-899 (also from South Stoa, well VII), but both incomplete. Also similar to Agora object P-5798 (Rotroff 1997, Agora 29, cat. 1180) and P-23300 (Rotroff 1997, Agora 29, cat. 1182) for basic Hellenistic type, but with different spouts</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
